Rakesh Kumar

Address: L-1189, Mangol Puri, New Delhi - 110083 +91 9873 924 772 | rakeshpersonal@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Creative technologist with **8.5+ years** of experience doing Front-End Web Development adhering to Web Standards and best practices. Highly motivated, detail oriented, and passionate advocate of emerging front-end technologies. Ability to learn new tools and concepts quickly while working independently or in a team environment and high-profile clients.

OBJECTIVE

To secure a challenging position in the corporate sector where I can apply my technical skills and experience and be a part of team that helps to achieve the organization success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SAPIENT GLOBAL MARKET

Sr. Interactive Developer (Since March 2015 to Preset)

Interactive developer specialized in JavaScript, Node JS, Express, Gulp, HTML, CSS and Web Standards. Have done large scale front-end development on BMO financial website as a lead front-end developer. Taken care of all the backend and front-end functionalities, API calls, raw JSON transformation (with help of lodash), optimization of API calls, performance improvements and others.

- 1. Render application on server side with the help of Node JS and Express.
- 2. Used EJS (embedded JS) to render data on front-end.
- 3. Created functionality of Download PDF and CSV for performance data and factsheet which contains the information of funds
- 4. Implemented the High Chart with custom modification to show the performance of funds.
- 5. Make application compatible with WCAG 2.0 standards.
- 6. Responsive with tablet and desktop

DAMCO GROUP

Sr. Software Engineer (Since March 2013 to March 2015)

Responsibilities included front-end development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, Angular JS and Graphic Designing of Website UI, Hybrid and Native Apps. Used Bootstrap and custom CSS to make the websites responsive and browser compatible.

- 1. Develop Angular App using IONIC framework
- 2. Develop more than 10 websites used WordPress
- 3. Used JavaScript, jQuery and CSS3 to make website more interactive.
- 4. Used latest technologies and best practices and web standards.

18th TECHNOLOGY

Sr. Web Designer (Since January 2011 to March 2013)

Under this organization responsibility included front-end development of website, maintaining website, handling team of 5 members, creating SEO friendly websites, theme implementation for WordPress and designing the UI and logo of websites and mobile Apps.

Skills: HTML5, CSS2/3, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Designing, Cross Browser Compatible Websites, WordPress, Photoshop, Illustrator

MAGNON SOLUTION

Assistant Manager (Since June 2010 to January 2011)

Responsibility included front-end development of website, maintaining website, handling team, creating SEO friendly websites, theme implementation for WordPress and designing the UI and logo of websites.

Skills: HTML5, CSS2/3, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Designing, Cross Browser Compatible Websites, Photoshop, Illustrator

MOSAIC ITES SERVICES

Web Designer (Since July 2008 to June 2010)

Responsibility included front-end development of website, maintaining website, creating SEO friendly websites and designing the UI and logo of websites.

Skills: HTML, CSS, iQuery, JavaScript, Cross Browser Compatible Websites, Photoshop, Illustrator

QUALIFICATIONS

Graduation in B.A. Political Science Honors from North Delhi University.

CERTIFICATIONS

ADIM(Advance Diploma in Multimedia)

2005 - 2008

Arena Multimedia - APTECH

CIC(Certificate in Computing)

2005 IGNOU

MEAN Stack and MongoDB Development

Techniques

Feb, 2017 Lynda.com | License 5E519E

SKILLS

 \rightarrow JavaScript \rightarrow Unit Testing \rightarrow HTML/HTML5 \rightarrow GIT

→ Node JS → ReduX → CSS2/3 → UI/UX Designing → Express JS → MobX → SASS/LESS → Photoshop → React JS → GULP/WEBPACK → Responsive Web Designing → Illustrator

→ React JS
→ GULP/WEBPACK
→ Responsive Web Designing
→ Angular JS
→ LODASH
→ Cross Browser/Platform Implementation

PERSONAL INFO

Father's Name: Mr. Ram Iqbal Marital Status: Married Nationality: Indian

Date of Birth : 16th Sep, 1984 Language : Hindi, English